It's hard to be cool when your Dad is Goofy.
A Goofy Movie is a adventure, comedy, romance film directed by Kevin Lima.
An endearing modern-day story about how the lovable Goof bonds with his
teenage son Max on a hilarious cross-country road trip.
En route to the ol' fishing hole, they find themselves
up to their floppy ears in misadventure!
Goofy (voice), played by Bill Farmer.
Max (voice), played by Jason Marsden.
P.J. (voice), played by Rob Paulsen.
Pete (voice), played by Jim Cummings.
Roxanne (voice), played by Kellie Martin.
Lester (voice), played by Kevin Lima.
A Goofy Movie is a 1995 American animated musical road comedy
film produced by Walt Disney Television Animation.
Directed by Kevin Lima, it is based on The Disney Afternoon television series Goof Troop (1992) created
by Robert Taylor and Michael Peraza, and serves as a standalone spin-off to the show.
Taking place three years after the events of Goof Troop, it follows Goofy and his now teenage son,
Max, as they embark on a misguided father-son fishing trip across the United States.
Former Walt Disney Company chairman Jeffrey Katzenberg suggested a storyline inspired by a
planned car trip with his daughter to Goofy Troop's story supervisor Jymn Magon.
Expanding Goofy as a character that would resonate with audiences, the film features the voices of Bill Farmer, Jim Cummings, and Rob Paulsen reprising their roles from the series
as Goofy, Pete, and P.J., respectively, while Jason Marsden replaces Dana Hill as Max, alongside Kellie Martin, Wallace Shawn, and Pauly Shore as new characters.
The rhythm and blues singer Tevin Campbell provides the vocals for Powerline, a fictional pop star
who prominently appears in the film, performing the songs "Stand Out" and "I 2 I".
Production lasted for two and a half years.
A Goofy Movie was released theatrically in the United States and
Canada on April 7, 1995, by Walt Disney Pictures.
Because it had been greenlit by Katzenberg, its release was
deemed by Disney to be a contractual obligation.
It received mixed reviews from critics and was a modest commercial success,
grossing $37.6 million against an $18 million production cost worldwide.
However, with its home media release, it garnered a cult following and
has become a more prominent property within Disney.
A direct-to-video sequel, An Extremely Goofy Movie,
was released on February 29, 2000.
A documentary about the making of A Goofy Movie, Not Just a Goof, premiered in 2024 and was released on
Disney+ in 2025 to coincide with the 30th anniversary of the film's original release.
The film explores themes of parent child relationship,
pop singer, cartoon, musical, road trip.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.